A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Grants O-R FA732F
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Ford Foundation Grants - O to R, 1941-2010
  - Princeton University (06400491), 1964 September 28-1974 September 27 (Reel R1219)
    Development of the new department of astrophysical sciences
    $685,000.00; $623,915.00
  - Princeton University (06500059), 1964 December 30-1974 December 29 (Reel R1305)
    Support of office of population research
    Saunders, Lyle
  - Princeton University (06500225), 1965 June 09-1967 June 08 (Reel R0250)
    Fellowship program in business administration and economics, 1965-66
    $21,265.00; $21,265.00
  - Princeton University (06600122), 1966 February 15-1966 August 14 (Reel R1003)
    Summer conference in computer sciences for electrical engineering faculty
    $17,250.00; $10,950.88
  - Princeton University (06600159), 1966 March 18-1977 September 30 (Reel R2494)
    Basic and Applied Research Program in Chinese Linguistics
    Bresnan, John J.; IIchman, Warren Frederick
  - Princeton University (06600177), 1966 April 08-1973 April 30 (Reel R4095)
    Research on the future of the international legal order
  - Princeton University (06600246), 1966 June 10-1968 June 09 (Reel R1004)
    Fellowship program in business administration and economics, 1966-67
    $25,935.00; $25,935.00
  - Princeton University (06700177), 1967 July 01-1976 June 30 (Reel R1328)
    Support for korean studies in the department of oriental studies
  - Princeton University (06700196), 1967 April 06-1968 April 05 (Reel R1018)
    Sponsorship of dr. Michael s. Burnhill, visiting fellow with office of pop. Rsch. For the 1966-67 academic year
    $3,150.00; $3,150.00
  - Princeton University (06700258), 1967 May 24-1974 August 31 (Reel R1441, Reel R1442)
    Continued support for program to improve the efficiency of doctoral studies in the humanities and social sciences
    $4,000,000.00; $4,000,000.00
  - Princeton University (06700334), 1967 June 29-1969 June 28 (Reel R1882)
    $33,820.00; $33,020.00
  - Princeton University (06700376), 1967 September 01-1974 August 31 (Reel R1123)
    Support of an expanded program in ecology
    $372,000.00; $372,000.00
  - Princeton University (06800094), 1967 December 27-1971 June 30 (Reel R2487)
    Research on models of urban growth and decline
    $228,534.00; $228,534.00
  - Princeton University (06800105), 1968 January 03-1971 June 30 (Reel R1088)
    Support of the princeton university cooperative undergraduate program for critical languages
    Office Of Vice President -Finance & Administration; International - Office of the Vice President [ID/OVP]
  - Princeton University (06800245), 1968 April 03-1977 June 30 (Reel R2323)
    Continued support of a program of studies on resource allocation and decision making at princeton university
    $440,000.00; $440,000.00
  - Princeton University (06800527), 1968 June 01-1969 May 31 (Reel R1983, Reel R1984)
    Partial support of a comparative analysis of negro and white college graduates
    $54,400.00; $54,400.00
  - Princeton University (06900043), 1968 October 25-1975 January 31 (Reel R2527)
    General support for princeton research program in economic development
    $285,000.00; $285,000.00
  - Princeton University (06900045), 1968 October 25-1971 June 30 (Reel R1592)
    Support for two conferences on the .band proposal. For flexible exchange rates within set margins
    $30,000.00; $29,896.00
  - Princeton University (06900230), 1969 March 03-1974 March 02 (Reel R1630)
    Assistance for the development of teaching and research in urban studies
    $650,000.00; $650,000.00
  - Princeton University (06900466), 1969 May 29-1970 May 28 (Reel R1945)
    Faculty research fellowship program in economics, political science and sociology, 1969-1970
    $23,612.00; $13,000.00
  - Princeton University (06900521), 1969 July 01-1971 June 30 (Reel R2004)
    Support of afro-american studies program
    $88,300.00; $88,300.00
  - Princeton University (06900551), 1969 July 01-1975 November 30 (Reel R1267)
    Support of expanded activities of the council of the humanities of princeton university
  - Princeton University (06900574), 1970 July 20-1971 December 31 (Reel R1917)
    Conferences on the reform of the international monetary system
    $5,563.04; $5,563.04
  - Princeton University (06900677), 1969 September 01-1970 August 31 (Reel R5653)
    Mid-career fellowship in population for mr. James b. Marshall
    $3,350.00; $3,350.00
    McLaughlin, Robert T.
  - Princeton University (07000217), 1970 April 07-1985 April 06 (Reel R4831)
    $271,000.00; $271,000.00
  - Princeton University (07000259), 1970 September 01-1972 August 31 (Reel R1305, Reel R3880)
    Support of research and consultation in economic demography
    $74,400.00; $74,400.00
  - Princeton University (07000528), 1970 August 01-1975 September 30 (Reel R1239)
    Preparation of a study guide to strategic concepts of arms control by the center of international studies
    $16,000.00; $15,071.00
  - Princeton University (07000591), 1970 (Reel R1706)
    Dissertation fellowships in ethnic studies for phd candidates
    $8,000.00; $8,000.00
  - Princeton University (07100092), 1971 January 01-1972 December 31 (Reel R1498)
    Partial support of a commission on the future of the college
  - Princeton University (07100258), 1971 September 01-1972 August 31 (Reel R1729)
    Dissertation fellowships in ethnic studies for ph.d. Candidates
  - Princeton University (07100355), 1971 June 08-1972 December 07 (Reel R1738)
    Program of faculty research fellowships in economics, political science and sociology, 1971-1972
    $28,791.00; $28,791.00
  - Princeton University (07100508), 1971 September 13-1976 June 30 (Reel R4445)
    Support of program in near eastern studies
  - Princeton University (07200150), 1972 March 21-1975 March 20 (Reel R1622)
    Transitional support for international studies
    $457,100.00; $457,100.00
    Middle East; North Asia; Global
  - Princeton University (07300094), 1973 February 01-1979 August 31 (Reel R4048)
    Cross-national study of mental health programs
    $149,000.00; $149,000.00
    Germany; Sweden
  - Princeton University (07300194), 1973 February 01-1974 December 31 (Reel R1208)
    Support for a comparative analysis of the projected energy demands for several alternative transportation systems
    $22,242.00; $22,242.00
  - Princeton University (07300562), 1973 June 29-1974 June 28 (Reel R1773)
    Conference on international monetary and the developing countries
    $7,000.00; $3,276.00
  - Princeton University (07500075), 1974 October 01-1975 September 30 (Reel R2382)
    Partial support for studies on international monetary problems and public affairs education by paul volcker
    Bell, Peter D.; Goodwin, Craufurd; Lisniewski, Theresa H.
  - Princeton University (07500116), 1974 October 01-1978 January 31 (Reel R2530)
    Aspects of international financial integration
    $66,340.00; $66,340.00
  - Princeton University (07500643), 1975 October 22-1980 December 31 (Reel R4123, Reel R4124)
    Research seminars and conferences organized by the program in near eastern studies
    $125,250.00; $125,250.00
    Barsalou, Judith Marie
    Middle East; Africa
  - Princeton University (07600073), 1975 December 01-1978 July 31 (Reel R2146)
    Support to strengthen the research and graduate training capabilities of ces in nuclear energy policy field
  - Princeton University (07600566), 1976 September 01-1988 April 05 (Reel R5599)
    General support of the office of population research
    Harkavy, Oscar; Horn, Majorie C.
  - Princeton University (07650094), 1975 November 01-1976 April 30 (Reel R1354)
    Support for editorial, printing and distribution cost of a manuscript for trustees of universities on managing endowments
  - Princeton University (07650427), 1976 June 15-1978 May 12 (Reel R2369)
    Project on women in the college curriculum
    $6,241.00; $6,241.00
  - Princeton University (07700253), 1977 March 01-1980 February 28 (Reel R3020)
    Support for research seminars on international monetary economics
    $42,900.00; $42,281.00
  - Princeton University (07700682), 1977 September 01-1980 June 30 (Reel R3009)
    Study of the impact of the restruction of medicaid funding for abortion
    Brown, Prudence; Teitelbaum, Michael S.
  - Princeton University (07750103), 1976 October 01-1977 March 31 (Reel R1615)
    Seminar on international monetary economics, november 1976
    $5,840.00; $5,840.00
  - Princeton University (07750305), 1977 April 01-1978 March 31 (Reel R2280)
    Partial support for the association of black princeton alumni conference
  - Princeton University (07750385), 1977 January 01-1977 June 30 (Reel R1280)
    Publication and distribution of a catalogue of italian drawings
  - Princeton University (07800038), 1978 January 01-1981 December 31 (Reel R3684)
    Support for a research project on solar energy policy
    $570,000.00; $570,000.00
  - Princeton University (07800050), 1977 November 01-1981 January 31 (Reel R2425)
    Support of curriculum develop. And related public policy training activities at the woodrow wilson school of public/int'l affairs
    Lisniewski, Theresa H.; Sharpe, Richard S.
  - Princeton University (07800469), 1978 June 01-1981 May 31 (Reel R2837)
    A study of the president's advisory organization conducted by professor fred i. Greenstein
    $52,195.00; $52,195.00
    Sharpe, Richard S.; Winnick, Louis
  - Princeton University (07850326), 1978 April 01-1981 June 30 (Reel R3543)
    Partial support of analysis of energy conservation and energy facility siting policies in new jersey
    $71,500.00; $71,500.00
  - Princeton University (07950677), 1979 September 01-1983 June 30 (Reel R3704, Reel R3751)
    Support for research on "north and south in the international economy"
    $32,330.00; $32,330.00
  - Princeton University (07950756), 1979 July 01-1981 November 30 (Reel R2693)
    Support of the final stage of study of the impacts of withdrawals of medicaid funded abortions
    $24,500.00; $24,500.00
  - Princeton University (08000570), 1980 September 01-1981 August 31 (Reel R4375)
    Study of the involuntary displacement of residents by urban reinvestment
  - Princeton University (08050148), 1979 November 21-1981 February 28 (Reel R2628)
    Study of professional networks among men and women in new jersey higher education administration
  - Princeton University (08150627), 1981 July 01-1982 June 30 (Reel R4190)
    Support for the planning phase of a study on the effects of the domestic policies of the reagan admin. By princeton urban and...
  - Princeton University (08200347), 1981 December 01-1986 June 30 (Reel R5284)
    Study of the state & local impact of cutbacks in federal domestic spending
    $1,238,400.00; $1,238,400.00
  - Princeton University (08350050), 1982 November 01-1983 June 30 (Reel R5088)
    Data analysis of social and biological determinants of child mortality
    $24,573.00; $19,338.00
  - Princeton University (08350080), 1982 November 01-1983 October 31 (Reel R4246)
    Partial support for a conference, "kampuchea in the 1980s: prospects and problems"
    Cambodia
  - Princeton University (08450779), 1984 October 03-1993 December 31 (Reel R6560)
    To underwrite the costs of putting selected haitian historical materials on microfiche
    Haiti
  - Princeton University (08500223), 1985 January 01-1991 December 31 (Reel R6193)
    Partial support for research and conference on inner asia
    $102,450.00; $100,917.00
  - Princeton University (08600650), 1986 August 01-1990 July 31 (Reel R5745)
    Grants to improve the quality of undergraduate education and recruit future faculty/freshman seminar program
    Stanley, Peter W.
  - Princeton University (08601058), 1986 September 01-1988 September 30 (Reel R7107)
    Impacts of business cycles & interest and exchange rate movements on rural manufacturing employment
    $52,732.00; $52,732.00
  - Princeton University (08650524), 1986 July 01-1991 June 30 (Reel R6086)
    Support for studies in indian political economy
    $50,000.00; $48,658.00
    Berman, Peter A.
  - Princeton University (08751078), 1987 September 01-1989 June 30 (Reel R5618)
    Support for a study of legislative strategy and public policy in the u.s. Congress
    $35,000.00; $34,883.00
  - Princeton University (08800417), 1987 September 01-1990 August 31 (Reel R6000)
    Support for scholars to participate in research on security and economy in the pacific basin
    $49,170.00; $49,170.00
    Japan; Europe
  - Princeton University (08800951), 1988 September 01-1993 June 30 (Reel R6424)
    Improve the teaching of the social sciences at the undergraduate level (006)
  - Princeton University (08850013), 1987 January 01-1987 December 31 (Reel R5307)
    Services and expenses of the econometric research program for the program on economics education and research in china, 1986-87
  - Princeton University (08900212), 1989 January 01-1989 December 31 (Reel R6031)
    Summer institutes for minority undergraduates to prepare for graduate public policy & international affairs studies
    $82,500.00; $82,500.00
    Diaz, William A.; Heginbotham, Stanley J. (Stanely Jay)
  - Princeton University (08950527), 1989 February 01-1991 August 31 (Reel R6326)
    Support for a book on u.s. Policy toward illegal substance abuse & trade including analyses of current & alternative drug strategies
  - Princeton University (09000801), 1990 June 01-1994 February 28 (Reel R6629)
    Partial support for research on international cooperation in response to aids
    $150,000.00; $149,175.91
  - Princeton University (09050350), 1989 September 01-1990 August 31 (Reel R5988)
    Partial support for research & a conference on the effects of public opinion on u.s. Central american policy during the reagan admin
    Heginbotham, Stanley J. (Stanely Jay)
  - Princeton University (09100594), 1991 July 01-1999 June 30 (Reel R7948)
    To create seminars on cultural diversity that link study of cultural phenomena to encounters with diverstiy in student life (014)
    Wilkerson, Margaret B. (Margaret Buford)
  - Princeton University (09200106), 1991 September 01-1998 August 31 (Reel R7966)
    For a project on "external dimensions of structural adjustment, reform and growth in developing countries and eastern europe" (023)
    $650,351.00; $650,351.00
    Wasow, Bernard
    Europe, Eastern; Africa; Global
  - Princeton University (09200585), 1992 July 01-1994 June 30 (Reel R6625)
    Support to study the relationship between economic growth, international trade and the environment
    $85,000.00; $83,700.86
  - Princeton University (09251053), 1992 June 01-1993 September 30 (Reel R6556)
    Partial support for a conference on arms control and the environment
    $39,000.00; $39,000.00
  - Princeton University (09251341), 1992 September 01-1994 December 31 (Reel R6661)
    Research and publication on history of the un african training and research center for women and un development fund for women
    Rights And Social Justice Program [RSJ]; Africa & The Middle East [AME]; Rural Poverty & Resources Program [RPR]
    Campbell, Elizabeth C.; Neuborne, Helen; Wadia, Anna
  - Princeton University (09501531), 1995 September 01-2000 December 31 (Reel R8591)
    Coord. & implem. Proj. Integrating int'l scholarship into u.s. Women's studies prog. & gender res. Into area or int'l studies progs.
  - Princeton University (09550300), 1995 February 01-1995 October 31 (Reel R6969)
    Partial support for a conference on "learning from operation restore hope: somalia revisited"
    Ispahani, Mahnaz Z.; Wiseman, Geoffrey
    SoMalia
  - Princeton University (09700117), 1996 September 01-1999 August 31 (Reel R7898)
    Support for interdisciplinary workshops and seminars that bring together faculty & students from the social sciences & area studies
  - Princeton University (09750284), 1997 January 01-1997 December 31 (Reel R7613)
    Support for a conference on religious diversity and campus life: looking ahead to the 21st century
    Buchanan, Constance H.; Zwerling, L. Steven
  - Princeton University (09950524), 1999 February 01-2000 January 31 (Reel R8565)
    Partial support for preparation of papers stemming from a scholarly conference and for documentation of the proceedings
    $25,900.00; $25,900.00
    United States; Literature--African American authors--Study and teaching; African American authors -- Congresses
  - Princeton University (10050122), 1999 September 01-2002 February 28 (Reel R8867)
    Final support for the research project entitled "transnational communities: their origins and effects among latin american immigrants in the united states"
    United States; West Indies; Emigration and immigration -- Research -- United States; Emigration and immigration -- Research -- Latin America
  - Princeton University (10050126), 2000 January 01-2003 December 31 (Reel R9162)
    Support of research for a scholarly book on how belief in exclusive access to divine truth came historically to shape the development of christianity
    $175,200.00; $175,200.00
    United States; Christianity -- Essence, genius, nature; Christianity -- Origin
  - Princeton University (10050155), 1999 November 01-2000 October 31 (Reel R8669)
    To develop a longitudinal research project to evaluate the impact on african american and hispanic students of recent changes in college admission policy in the state of texas
    Balan, Jorge
    United States; Universities and colleges--Texas--Admission--Research; African Americans -- Education, Higher; Hispanic Americans -- Education, Higher
  - Princeton University (10100409), 2001 January 01-2003 June 30 (Reel R8791)
    Support for an internship program that places computer science and engineering students with public interest media policy organizations
    United States; Information technology -- Study and teaching
  - Princeton University (10200164), 2001 October 01-2003 September 30 (Reel R9087)
    For research on contemporary religious diversity and interfaith engagement in the United States
    $321,700.00; $317,850.33
  - Princeton University (10500390), 2005 July 01-2006 December 31 (Reel R9129)
    To conduct research for a book on historical interpretations of the Book of Revelation
    Educational Opportunity and Scholarship
  - Princeton University Press (05700063), 1956 December 31-1967 January 30 (Reel R2445)
    Stimulation of publication in the humanities and social sciences
    $204,240.00; $204,240.00
  - Princeton University Press (07000222), 1970 April 01-1972 March 31 (Reel R1661)
    Support for a special supplement to "world politics" on "theory and policy in international relations"
    Cyr, Arthur I.
  - Principia College (05600466), 1956 June 29-1966 June 28 (Reel R0306)
    $192,500.00; $192,500.00
  - Principia College (05601000), 1956 June 29-1957 June 28 (Reel R0336)
  - Prison Communities International (10150364), 2000 August 01-2001 August 31 (Reel R8691)
    To support a conference on the criminal justice system and its impact on youth, women, and the children of those incarcerated
    United States; Criminal Justice, Administration of -- United States -- Congresses
  - Private Agencies Collaborating Together, Inc. (PACT) (09150782), 1991 July 01-1993 July 31 (Reel R6578)
    Support to strengthen the institutional development of organizations concerned with small enterprise development
  - Private Agencies Collaborating Together, Inc. (PACT) (09351097), 1993 June 01-1997 April 30 (Reel R7737, Reel R8382)
    Support for vietnamese participation in annual dialogue meetings of the vietnamese-american youth project
  - Private Agencies Collaborating Together, Inc. (PACT) (10001263), 2000 June 01-2002 November 30 (Reel R9001)
    Research on past experiences and assessment of future needs of ngo advocacy capacity development in indonesia
    $212,500.00; $212,500.00
    Indonesia; Civil society -- Indonesia -- Citizen participation; Non-governmental organizations--Indonesia--Research; Social Justice--Indonesia
  - Private Agencies Collaborating Together, Inc. (PACT) (10250490), 2002 February 01-2004 March 14 (Reel R9217)
    For the implementation of an organizational capacity assessment program
    $156,850.00; $156,850.00
    China; Non-governmental organizations--China; Civil society -- China
  - Private Agencies in International Development (08450478), 1984 April 01-1984 September 30 (Reel R5281)
    Partial transitional support for the merger of 2 private voluntary agencies
  - Private Concerns, Inc. (07850209), 1978 January 01-1978 March 31 (Reel R3066)
    Support for an ex offender employment program
  - Private Corporation for the Social Development of Conchali (09251269), 1992 August 15-1994 March 31 (Reel R7238, Reel R7465)
    Support for new community development corporation in santiago
    Cartier, William J.
  - Private Industry Council of the City of New York, Inc. (08550289), 1985 January 01-1986 December 31 (Reel R5485)
    Support to establish comprehensive competencies program for individuals trying to qualify for upper-level training programs
  - Private Sector Foundation (10051637), 2000 July 01-2003 June 30 (Reel R8983)
    Support to plan a strategy to build communities' capacitys to manage income from the harvesting of wild coffee
    Menzies, Nicholas K.; Nuvunga, Milagre
    Uganda; Small business--Services for--Uganda; Wild plant trade--Uganda; Coffee -- Marketing -- Uganda
  - Private Sector Foundation (10152039), 2001 September 01-2002 August 31 (Reel R9096)
    To explore means of attaining financial sustainability, devise strategies for asset development and improve program delivery by transforming itself into a grant-making foundation
    $75,000.00; $33,692.00
    Uganda; Humanitarianism--Uganda
  - Private Sector Initiative for Corporate Governance Trust (09951803), 1999 September 01-2001 August 31 (Reel R8522)
    Support for a project to develop a code of best practices for corporate governance in kenya
  - Private Sector Initiative for Corporate Governance Trust (10001742), 2000 August 01-2003 March 31 (Reel R8984)
    Support for programs, institutional development and capacity building for the promotion of corporate governance in Kenya
    $320,000.00; $320,000.00
    Kenya; Corporate governance -- Law and legislation -- Kenya
  - Private Sector Initiative Joint Education Trust (09501176), 1995 August 01-2000 April 30 (Reel R8724)
    Support for a workers higher education project
  - Private Sector Initiative Joint Education Trust (09701155), 1997 June 01-1998 May 31 (Reel R7957)
    Research suport for national community service partnership programs for higher education in south africa
    Southern Africa (Johannesburg); KC & F - Office of the Vice President
    Aguerrebere, Joseph; Fehnel, Richard A. (Richard Allen)
  - Private Sector Initiative Joint Education Trust (09801697), 1998 July 01-2003 December 31 (Reel R9272)
    Support for community-higher education partnership initiative in south africa
    $2,233,000.00; $2,233,000.00
    Bawa, Ahmed
    South Africa; Education, Higher -- South Africa; Educational equalization -- South Africa
  - Private Sector Initiatives Corporation (10051598), 2000 June 01-2002 December 31 (Reel R9032)
    Support to conduct ratings of nigerian micro finance institutions and provide technical assisitance to them
    $100,000.00; $43,023.93
    Nigeria; Development economics -- Nigeria; Microfinance--Nigeria
  - Pro Helvetia (09650548), 1996 January 01-1996 December 31 (Reel R7192, Reel R8698)
    Support for documentation and activities of a traditional music troupe in port said
    Davies, Kristina N.; Taylor, Elizabeth
  - Pro Helvetia (10151285), 2001 February 01-2003 January 31 (Reel R9185)
    For a traditional music teaching program
    El Husseiny, Basma